<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feature
      id="com.buglabs.osgi.concierge.feature"
      label="Concierge Tools for Eclipse"
      version="1.0.0.qualifier"
      provider-name="Bug Labs, Inc."
      plugin="com.buglabs.osgi.concierge.ui">

   <description url="http://buglabs.net/software/concierge_tools">
      Concierge Tools for Eclipse provides basic design-time and run-time
support for the Concierge OSGi framework.  Concierge is a R3
OSGi implementation designed to be small and fast, and is ideal
for resource constrained devices and applications.
More information regarding Concierge, as well as source code, can be found at http://concierge.sourceforge.net/.

A binary form of Concierge is included as a part of these tools in the com.buglabs.osgi.concierge.runtime plugin.
   </description>

   <copyright>
      Eclipse Tools for Concierge is Copyright Bug Labs, Inc..  All
rights reserved.
Concierge is Copyright Jan S. Rellermeyer, Information and Communication
Systems Research Group (IKS), Institute for Pervasive Computing,
ETH Zurich.
All rights reserved.
   </copyright>

   <license url="http://buglabs.net/license/eclipse_tools">
      Copyright (c) 2007 Bug Labs, Inc.
All rights reserved.

Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or
without modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions
are met:
   - Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright
notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.
   - Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above
copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer
in the documentation and/or other materials provided with the
distribution.
   - Neither the name of Bug Labs, Inc. nor the names of its contributors may be used to endorse or promote products derived from this
software without specific prior written permission.

THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS
&quot;AS IS&quot; AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED
TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR
PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT OWNER OR CONTRIBUTORS
BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY,
OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT
OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS;
OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY,
WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR
OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF
ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.
   </license>

   <url>
      <update label="Bug Labs External Development Site" url="http://bugblade.com/cte"/>
   </url>

   <plugin
         id="com.buglabs.osgi.concierge.runtime"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="com.buglabs.osgi.concierge.ui"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="com.buglabs.osgi.concierge.core"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

   <plugin
         id="com.buglabs.osgi.concierge.doc"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="0.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

</feature>
